# 这个菜目前是我吃过最好的九转大肠
This dish is the best Braised Intestines I have ever eaten.
# 九转大肠
Braised Intestines in Brown Sauce
# 那时候我师父教我的
My master taught me at that time.
# 有两个我穿好了的 肥的这块大肠头
There are two intestines that I have threaded already. This fat one is a fat end.
# 我再演练一遍穿这个大肠
I'll demonstrate how to thread the intestine again
# 油啊我都择干净了
I have removed all the oil.
# 刚干你用什么洗的 醋跟面粉 还有花椒
What did you use to wash? Vinegar, flour and pepper
# 搓了以后给它冲干净了
Wash it away after rubbing
# 反复搓有十多分钟
Repeat rubbing for about than ten minutes
# 每个师傅啊 手法也不一样
Every cook has his own way to do this.
# 有搁醋的 有搁盐的 他那搁醋搁盐呢
Some use vinegar, some use salt. He uses both.
# 就是去掉肠子上面那层粘液
It is to remove the layer of mucus on the intestines.
# 里外翻 套上
Turn inside out, and put it over.
# 这里边的油 它叫水油
The oil inside is called water oil
# 水油过去都把它撕下来以后呢
We used to tear it off
# 专门炼一种大油
and used it to refine lard.
# 煎灌肠啊 做一些下水的菜 它出来以后香
It would make some dishes such as Fried enema, or other offal dishes, smell good.
# Turn inside out, and after doing that
# 一定要用牙签给它扎上 锁住了
It must be tied with a toothpick so it would be locked
# 它省的跑 不扎就完蛋  用牙签给它别上
and would not be out of space. It would be screwed otherwise.
Use toothpick to tie it.
# 有时候你还得多扎两个
Sometimes you have to use two more toothpicks to do this.
# 所以每个细节都很重要
So every detail is important.
# 你看 扎完了 牙签给它别上
You see, we have used toothpick to tie it up.
# 这边上留着点 到时候做一个别的菜
I’ll leave the ends as what they are and make another dish.
# 咱就是焯水 搁点黄酒
we blanch with some yellow rice wine.
# 搁点葱姜
Add few scallion and ginger.
# 人家说九转大肠 各味都能吃出来
There is a saying that the you can taste all five favours in Nine Turn Intestines,
# 五味 酸甜苦辣咸 人生五味
sour, sweet, bitter, spicy and salty, so called “Five tastes of life”.
# 网友开玩笑说 人说了 不是五味
Netizens joked that it's not five flavors
# 是六味 脏器味 没有这脏器味还不行
It’s six flavors, organ flavor, and it’s not good without organ flavor.
# 苦是糖色的苦 酸是米醋的酸
Bitter comes from sugar, sour comes from rice vinegar acid.
# 辣是胡椒粉的辣 枣红色 甜压酸
Spicy comes from pepper, maroon, The sweet favour would cover the sour favour.
# 回口儿有肉桂粉 跟砂仁粉的香气
It has aromas of cinnamon powder and amomum powder.
# 这是咱市场买的肉桂粉
This is the cinnamon powder bought in our market.
# 网友看一下这个砂仁
Netizens, let’s take a look at this amomum.
# 砂仁粉有卖现成的 咱今天没买着
Ready-made Amomum powder is available in the market, we didn’t manage to buy it today
# 没买着咱就自己磨一下
Even though we didn't find it, we can grind it ourselves.
# 就跟似的 咱焙花椒 小火
In the same way as we roast sichuan peppercorn, use low heat.
# 您看焯水的时候它这个肠子是鼓起来的
The intestine bulges while blanching.
# 用牙签 一扎 扎它一下 要不它就崩了
Use a toothpick to pierce it, or it will collapse.
# 牙签别上有两个好处
There are two benefits of using toothpicks to tie it up,
# 第一它把空气给放出去了
First, it let the air out.
# 第二 它不容易跑 这还挺好
Second, it restricts the intestine to move, which is pretty good.
# 多焯会 焯到紧实了 沫子打掉
Boil it until it is firm, then remove the foam.
# 你看这肠子 焯透了咱就给它捞出来
Look at this intestine, scoop it up until it’s done.
# 还冲洗冲洗吗
Do we need to rinse it?
# 冲洗冲洗 不冲洗有味儿
Yes, otherwise it would smell.
# 还有烧好的开水 倒过来
We have some boiled water, get some over.
# 现在就放吗 放吧大爷 放 没事
Now? Yes, Da Ye, now, it’s ok.
# 这肠子挺棒的
The intestine is great.
# 大料 干辣椒 桂皮 小茴香 花椒
Anise, Dried chili, Cassia, Cumin, Sichuan Peppercorn
# 搁点葱
Add some scallion.
# 姜皮最好 别浪费了 姜皮搁上
Ginger peel is great, don’t waste it, put some ginger peels.
# 咱们给它加点黄酒
Let’s add some yellow rice wine.
# 白酒和黄酒一块加更好
White spirit and yellow rice wine are better together
# 去腥 白酒 都加上
To wipe off the raw smell, add a lot of while Spirit.
# 这味一下子就提起来
Now we have the flavor.
# 少搁点酱油 这还不能颜色太重
Add a little of soy sauce, otherwise the colour would become too dark.
# 你还得炒糖色 少搁点
We also need to fry sugar. A bit, not too much
# 准备压一下
Get ready to use pressure cooker.
# 这不搁盐什么的么 不搁盐
I don’t think we need to add salt or other spices. No.
# 没有高压锅咱就直接煮 一个多小时
Boil it for over one hour if we don’t have a pressure cooker.
# 白酒味出来了 这会它的脏器味就没有了
When we can smell the white spirit, then the organ smell is gone.
# 让白酒挥发一下 再炖一下
Let the white spirit volatilize for a while.
# 你在里边一焖 酒焖出来味不出去
If you stew it, the alcohol would volatilize but the flavor wouldn’t.
# 乙醇也有臭味
Ethanol smells.
# 但是有一样这酒不能用曲酒
Cannot use yeast wine.
# 曲酒是臭的
It smells.
# 您看这个药料 咱刚才搁的
Look at the spices that we just put in.
# 大料瓣就两三个
Just two or three anises.
# 不能把脏器味过多的给压过去
Cannot remove the organ smell completely.
# 为什么人说要六味 一定要有那脏器味
Why we say there are six flavour, the organ smell is a must.
# 味差不多了 给它倒出来 慢点
It is almost done, pour it out slowly.
# 这小锅还挺好
The small pot is nice.
# 压上 五十分钟 多焖会
Press it for 50 minutes.
# 到点了出锅喽
It’t time to get it out of pot.
# 真香 这处理的真好 真烂糊
The treatment is really good that it smells so good and soft.
# 连压带煮 你看多漂亮
Look how pretty it is after pressing and boiling.
# 这边晾着点 我准备工作做一下
Let’s put it aside while I do some preparation.
# 小香菜末 最好要香菜梗
Minced parsley and some stem would be better.
# 牙签这时候就给它拔掉了
Remove the toothpicks now
# 这时候它不会散了 散不了了
since the intestines is fixed.
# 切一下 这厚度要多厚
Cut it. How wide it should be?
# 跟原来扳指似的 大扳指 两公分多一点
Same as the thumb ring, big thumb ring, just more than 2cm.
# 一般我们在店里头做完了
When we do it in the restaurant,
# 就直接放冰箱 它不会散
we put it inside fridge so that it would not fall apart.
# 但是今天刚出锅的 咱用牙签给它别上
But the one today we just get it out of pot, let’s tie it up with toothpicks.
# 要不它就散了
Otherwise it would fall apart.
# 等做好了以后再把牙签抽出来
And remove the toothpicks when it is done.
# 只有你有这么大胆子敢做
Only you have the courage to do it.
# 家里着急也可以这么做
If you are urgent, you can do it as well.
# 大肠必须得烂糊
The intestine has to be soft.
# 第一步炒糖色
The first step is to fry sugar.
# 油水炒 少搁点油
With a little of oil and water.
# 行了 这油够热了 倒出来
Ok, the oil is hot enough, pour it out.
# 水油炒 冰糖
Fry crystal sugar with oil and water.
# 冰糖必须水油 化的快
Crystal sugar have to use water and oil so that it melt fast.
# 相比好掌握一些 颜色还好看
Easier to control and the color looks better.
# 现在冒的全都是大泡
Now they are all big bubbles.
# 九转大肠 苦味虽然算一个味道
Nine Turn Intestines, bitterness is a flavour,
# 不是非要把糖炒苦了
but that doesn’t mean to fry the sugar til it is bitter.
# 就略微有点那种焦糖的糊化的味道
Until it taste like burned caramel.
# 要炒苦了也不对了
It is wrong to fry it until it is bitter.
# 这个糖不停的在锅里边搅动
Keep stirring the sugar in the wok
# 现在开始有变化了
Now we see the change.
# 现在冒小泡 大泡变小泡
Now they are small bubbles, big bubbles becomes small bubbles.
# 颜色稍微的变黄一点 茶色
Until the color turn yellow, or brown.
# 稀的溜儿的跟蜂蜜似的 就是金黄色
Watery like honey, golden color.
# 这时候拔丝最好了
Now it’s the best status to make candied dishes
# 往下继续 这看这个糖基本不冒泡了
Keep going, now the there are no bubbles.
# 适当这火小一点 拿下来
Turn down the heat a little bit, take it down.
# 然后变成深褐色 酱油色 冒烟
And now it turned deep brown, color of soy sauce with smoke.
# 这个时候这个糖色就好了
Now we finished frying sugar.
# 差不多了 可以了
Almost, now it is done.
# 倒料酒（黄酒）
Add some yellow rice wine.
# 加水加（黄酒）都可以
Water and yellow rice wine both work.
# 这是所谓的糖色 备好
This is the so call sugar colour, now we have it.
# 用砂锅 砂锅出来更香
Use casserole so it taste better.
# 来二伯给倒点油 够不够 够了
Er Bai, add some oil. Enough? Enough.
# 我看油够热的 葱姜
The oil is hot enough,
# 葱姜下锅煸炒 煸出香味来
Stir scallion and ginger until it smell good.
# 少搁点花椒粒 干辣椒 去一下腥味
A bit sichuan peppercorn, dried chill to get rid of the smell.
# 在家有砂锅用砂锅
When you are at home, use casserole if you have one.
# 没砂锅用铁锅也可以 砂锅不容易糊锅
You can also use wok if you don’t have casserole. It is less likely to burn it when using casserole.
# 因为它糖很大
Because there are a lot of sugar in it.
# 料给它搁进去了 挨着个儿
Add other ingredients one by one.
# 葱姜的香气给它腾出来
Ensure the aroma of spring onion and ginger is freed from it
# 把火关小点
Turn down the heat a bit.
# 料油（黄酒）
Yellow rice wine.
# 煮肥肠的老汤 加进去了
Add the soup that we boiled the intestines.
# 这时候开始加味了
Now we add spices.
# 糖 糖的量要大一点
Sugar, a lot of sugar.
# 白胡椒粉
white pepper powder
# 酱油老味道
soy sauce, old traditional flavor
# 味道强 老味道
good taste, old traditional flavor
# 醋 来点醋 米醋
vinegar, add some vinegar, rice vinegar.
# 二十克 因为它要㸆一下 待会它要挥发
20 grams, give it time to volatile.
# 这时候可以找颜色了 糖色可以加了
Now we adjust the color, add the sugar color.
# 炒好的糖色下锅 颜色很关键 红亮
Add the sugar color, the color is very important, bright red.
# 颜色不够 接着加
The color is too light, more.
# 再加点糖色 漂亮 慢慢㸆着吧
More sugar color, nice, now give it time.
# 该尝尝口儿了 把味定一下
Let’s try it and test it.
# 自己还嘿呢
You even “Hey” yourself.
# 再加点盐这会儿
Add more salt.
# 这颜色还不够
The color is not deep enough.
# 五十克的冰糖都给加上了
Add all 50 grams of crystal sugar.
# 逐步的找颜色 烹调前烹调中
Adjust the color progressively, before cooking, while cooking.
# 逐渐的在加颜色加味 逐步的加味
Adjust the color and the taste progressively.
# 颜色可以了 待会出来正好
Now we have the color is good, and it would be the right color when we pour it out.
# 这时候就开始把葱姜挑出来了 挑干净
Now pick out all the scallion and ginger.
# 这砂锅有点小 应该换一锅
The casserole is a bit too small, get another one.
# 那就使那大锅吧
Then use the big wok.
# 给它倒出来 按四川话说不好耍啊
Pout it out, “Bu Hao Shua” in Sichuan dialect.
# 耍不开 搁这
Not easy to do in a small casserole.
# 这时候葱姜就好挑了
Now it is easy to pick out scallion and ginger.
# 这大肠
Oh, the intestine.
# 接着就是㸆 待会就㸆黏糊了 尝尝味
Now we just wait until it is sticky, give a try.
# 这味好吃
It tastes good.
# 晃悠收汁 晃锅收汁
Shake the wok and all liquids are reduced and absorbed.
# 各种味都出来了 酸甜苦辣咸
Now we have all the flavours: sweet, sour, bitter, spicy and salty.
# 再加点胡椒粉 缺点辣味
Add some pepper powder, it is not spicy enough.
# 因为它是酸甜苦辣
Because it should be sweet, sour, bitter, spicy and salty.
# 这个辣不是靠辣椒的辣
The spicy flavor doesn’t come out of chilli,
# 它是靠白胡椒粉的辣
it come out of white pepper powder.
# 漂亮
Beautiful.
# 你看见没有 它自然收汁
Did you see that? The liquids are reduced and concentrated themselves.
# 越来越好看了
It looks better and better.
# 好关火吧 关小火
Nice, turn down the fire, til small fire.
# 来一大翻勺吧 翻一下也行
Let’s overturn the wok, once is fine.
# 您看这亮度 这会儿该砂仁粉了
Look at the brightness, now it’s the time to add amomum powder.
# 砂仁粉
Amomum powder
# 肉桂粉 少来点 去腥增香 撒上
Cinnamon powder, a little bit, it would remove odor and make it smell good, add it.
# 你就一个一个出吧
Pour them out one by one.
# 出盘的时候要把牙签要拔掉
Remove the toothpicks when dish up.
# 这规格高了  魏刚强 手艺强
It is of high standard, Gangqiang Wei, of high skills.
# 咱挂汁 明油来点 撒上
Sprinkle some clear oil.
# 这汁儿全给搁上
With all the sauce.
# 这点汁收的 绝了
The liquids are reduced and concentrated in a such fantastic way.
# 香菜末点中间
Put some minced cilantro in the middle.
# 这样就更绿好看了 美观了
It has some green color and looks better.
# 来点山楂解腻 山楂罐头就行
Add some hawthorn so the dish wouldn’t be greasy, hawthorn works here.
# 这儿来俩
Two over here.
# 我什么话都不说
No words can express my feeling,
# 用我的行动来表达一下我的心情
let me use my action.
# 感谢大爷
Thank you Da Ye.
# 甜酸苦辣咸
Sweet, sour, bitter, spicy and salty,
# 这几种味道完全你都体现出来了
you can taste all of the flavours,
# 味道恰到好处
with the right amount.
# 甜又不是很甜
Not too sweet.
# 大爷 这道菜
Da Ye, this dish
# 凝结着我跟小魏几十年的感情
condense my relationship with Xiao Wei for decades
# 久违了 好长时间没做
Long lost, I hadn’t made this one for so long.
# 今天又看到这道菜 我也很激动
I am also excited to see the dish,
# 而且在这种条件之下
under this circustance.
# 他敢做 做得这么好
He dared to do this, and did it so well.
# 这个菜是目前我吃过最好的九转大肠
This is the best Nine Turn Intestines I have ever had.
# 人生五味 通过这菜品出来了
We can tell “Five tastes of life from this dish.
# 厨师的五个境界 你也出来了
You also reached the five realms in the chef field.
# 你是高手
You are a master.